<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gilhooley</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 18:43:59 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 18:43:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Start of Backpacking: Munich and Salzburg</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally got to meet up with Blake, Tony and Adam to start my last two weeks in Europe. Our first two stops are Munich and Salzburg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;munich&quot;&gt;Munich&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-1-arrivals&quot;&gt;Day 1: Arrivals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam and I left Dusseldorf early on the 1st to make the long travel to Munich. 
We are old pros at the train systems now so the journey went by without an incident.
After making it to the main train station, we then took a ride out to the airport so we could pick up Blake. 
Blake had spent the summer working for Friendsy at Princeton.
He is spending the money from that to travel Europe all through August and most of September.
Making it back to the city, we checked into the AirBnb fine but our host, Markus, was no where to be found.
Overall the apartment was completely adequete and no more. He had an interesting choice in decorations and refridgerator stickers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/MunichAcademy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Munich Academy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For dinner we stopped at a beer garden for bratwurst and sauerkraut so that Blake could get the authentic German experience.
We walked the whole city in the evening, seeing some amazing sights and buildings.
Because we didn’t have a guide book we couldn’t quite make out what each building was, but they were certainly pretty to look at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the highlights of the night was finding a park where there was a person playing the Sitar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony was supposed to arrive in the evening. This summer he had been working in Belfast, Ireland and he was taking a bus from Berlin.
Tony had forgetten about the time zone difference from Ireland to Berlin.
After walking around Berlin he found out he was an hour late for his bus! 
He could buy another bus to Munich, but it would arrive around 4 AM, so the whole gang didn’t arrive until the second day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-2-dachau&quot;&gt;Day 2: Dachau&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Dachau.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dachau&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left in the morning to visit Dachau. We arrived early enough that most of the other visitors had not arrived and we could have some more personal moments with the memorials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning fog made the atmosphere feel even more hallowed and the art exhibits were very powerful. 
This statue was located outside of the main officer and it represents the strength and spirit that the prisoners showed throughout their persecution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-2-hofbrauhaus&quot;&gt;Day 2: Hofbrauhaus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Hofbrauhaus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hofbrauhaus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After resting for a bit at the apartment we went out for a good dinner at the famous Hofbrauhaus.
This is one of the largest beer gardens in the world and it can seat over 1,300 people.
For dinner I had Schweinshaxe which is a massive ‘pork knuckle’, a liter of great German beer, and a pretzel the size of my face.
We did some more walking after dinner but didn’t see anything important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-3-neuschwanstein-and-hohenschwangau&quot;&gt;Day 3: Neuschwanstein and Hohenschwangau&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/CastleCity.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Castle City&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our last day in Munich we wanted to see Neuschwanstein, a giant castle that Walt Disney supposedly used as inspiration for the Disney logo.
It was a 3 hour train ride to get there, during which I managed to avoid paying for a ticket by another series of mistakes.
The castle area was incredibly beautiful and scenic, with massive mountains and a crystal blue lake. 
This beauty was marred a little by the large amounts of tourists which swarmed the small shops, resturaunts, and hiking trails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Hohenschwangau.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hohenschwangau&quot; /&gt;
We saw Hohenschwangau first. This castle was the original castle for the royal family of Bavaria, while Neuschwanstein was built for Ludwig the Second so that he could have even more space.
The rooms were beautiful and gilded to excess, but the tour was sparse and gave very little information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Neuschwanstein.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Neuschwanstein&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Neuschwanstein tour was better simply because the castle was more decadent. 
The walls were covered with scenes from Ludwig’s favorite stories and myths, which each sets of rooms having a different theme.
This castle was for Ludwig alone: he was not married yet and he did not like to appear in public. 
He seemed to be a lover of culture and art but he was a bit of a shut-in. 
The castle was built in 1869 but he devoted it to the Middle Age styles, which he adored.
On his mysterious death the castle was never finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;salzburg&quot;&gt;Salzburg&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Salzburg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Salzburg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stayed in Salzburg for one full day. 
We arrived at the Hostel still in time for the unlimited breakfast for 3.50 euros. 
I ate 3 bowls of Musli, which is a German cereal that I love a lot (its basically just oats and milk).
With that good start to our day, we set off into the city to see the big churches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/SalzDom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SalzDom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first church we saw was the Salzburger Dom, which was unbelievably large and beautiful.
The sheer, awesome scale of these churches left a big impression on me. 
I can’t imagine these being built even with modern tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon leaving the church we saw that Mozart’s Requiem was being played that night and there were still tickets available. 
We decided that this would be the best use of our money for the day and we bought 4 tickets for the show. 
Although I do not know a lot about choir and classical music, the space and music made for an unforgettable experience.
The ceilings were so high that any loud note would reverberate for a few seconds in a very beautiful way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/PetersAbby.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;PetersAbby&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other interesting thing we saw was Saint Peter’s Abby. It had a large connecting cemetary and a catacomb that was built into the cliffside. 
Walking though the catacombs it was clear that it was hewn by pretty rough tools.
There were much simpler altars in each of the rooms which provided a good contrast to the enormous churches we had been seeing earlier that day.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/Munich/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Munich/</guid>
        
        
        <category>germany</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weekend 25th: Adventures with the Bowers family in Jurbise</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Another great weekend! This is what Adam and I did in Belgium with the wonderful Bowers family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-bowers-family&quot;&gt;The Bowers Family&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My good friend Adam Cellon has also been in Germany these last two months, living in Duisberg. 
His family is originally from Virginia beach but because his dad works in the Navy they know families that are stationed all over the world.
The Bower family is one such family. 
They lived in Virginia but they have been stationed at the NATO base in Jurbise, Belgium for a little over a year.
The family consists of Mr. and Mrs. Bowers and their two kids, Ethan and Meghan who are 10 and 6 respectively. 
Meghan is an extremely rambuncious little girl who speaks half in English and half in French because she has been learning French in school.
She has a pet ladybug and wishes that she still could take gymnastics classes.
Ethan is attending classes on the base. 
He loves Legos and Minecraft, telling stories and explaining differences between Belgium and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The town of Jurbise is located 40 minutes outside of the city of Brussels. 
While the country of Belgium has four prominent languages (Flemish, French, Dutch, and German), French is dominant in this region.
Jurbise is a quaint town that sprung up in the middle of flat farmlands. 
The city itself has maybe 12 houses and a few streets, but like all things in Europe there is a beautiful brick church and plenty of things to see.
The horizon is filled with crops of potato and wheat as well as pastures for cows and donkeys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;getting-to-belguim&quot;&gt;Getting to Belguim&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam managed to figure out a way to cut our cost of travel in half; we would take a train to Belgium and then a bus back.
The train tickets were purchased through the Duestche Bahn website, but for some strange reason the tickets could only be mailed (instead of being printed out or downloaded to the DB app).
Adam received his tickets in two days, but for reasons unknown to me my tickets never arrived at my apartment in Dusseldorf.
The day of my journey I printed out my only piece of information, an email that claimed I had paid for these missing tickets.
I reasoned that we were almost never stopped for tickets in Germany, and that if we were, I could look confused and show them the email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam and I were stopped on all three of our trains by people looking for our tickets.
Each time I looked very apologetic and offered up my email and my American passport.
The ticket checkers had varying degrees of English abilities.
One looked very disappointed in me, another just kept walking after he heard English, but I made the journey without being fined or held by train authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The greatest part about the journey is that after getting internet at the Bowers house I receieved an email from DB. Because my ticket was lost in the mail, I was refunded the full train cost! My combination of good/bad luck had saved me 37 euros!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;saturday----pancakes-legos-puzzles-and-the-medieval-festival&quot;&gt;Saturday – Pancakes, Legos, Puzzles, and The Medieval Festival&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday brought us a day of uncertain rain (Mr. Bowers told us that Brussel’s weather was exactly the same as Seattle in terms of rainfall/sunny days).
We had all originally planned to ride RailBikes on Saturday, which involved a three hour bike ride on a repurposed railroad track, but the uncomfortable prospect of getting wet made us reconsider. 
We started the morning instead with one of America’s greatest inventions, the breakfast pancake. 
The chocalate chip pancakes were such a welcome suprise to a traveler who had grown a little homesick and more than a little tired with German food. 
With the pancakes weighing us down we had a lazy morning.
I read my kindle and built some minecraft legos with Ethan until lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/MedievalFestival.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Medieval Festival&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch we decided to go visit a French Medieval Festival that was in town for the weekend.
The festival was filled with families in old fashioned clothes who were fletching arrows and carrying large hunks of meat around.
There were rows and rows of extravagent medieval tents as if the fair were just an old fashion army camping out over the weekend.
It was clear that these families were sleeping in the tents over the weekend and we all admired the fact that they were here doing this in inclement weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/EthanArmor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ethan&#39;s Armor&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/EthanShield.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ethan&#39;s  Shield&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethan was in absolute heaven because at one tent we were able to hold shields and various swords, touch chainmail, and even wear a metal knight’s helmet.
Ethan kept trying to buy one of the wooden training swords, but Mrs. Bowers stopped him so he didn’t try to terrorize the surrounding neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sunday----grand-place-manneken-pis-chocolate-museum-and-the-royal-museums-of-fine-art&quot;&gt;Sunday – Grand Place, Manneken Pis, Chocolate Museum, and the Royal Museums of Fine Art&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early Sunday morning Adam and I headed out to the city of Brussels.
We started our morning with a great breakfast on the square of the Grand Place.
The Grand Place (pronounced Platz) has been important to Brussels since the 14th century and hosts a beautiful town hall adorned with gold and stone statues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/GrandPlace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Grand Place&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My breakfast was a smoked salmon omelette where Adam’s ended up being a basket of bread and a few pieces of fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/MannekenPis.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Manneken Pis&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near the square is a 61 cm tall bronze statue known as ‘Manneken Pis’.
This little guy is the greatest, partly because he is just a statue of a peeing child and partly because the entire city is obsessed with him.
There is a museum (which we sadly missed) where you can find over 600 of this guy’s little outfits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our morning adventures, we walked into Brussel’s Chocolate Museum. 
The highlight of the Museum was ‘tasting’ different types of chocolate to distinguish the differences in cocoa percentages.
I personally used that part of the tour to eat as much Belgium chocolate as possible, and the tour was totally worth our 5 euros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/BrusselsArt.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Museum of Fine Art&quot; /&gt;
Next we visited the Royal Museum of Fine Art.
The museum featured Flemmish painters from the 16th and 17th century.
There were also some beautiful landscape paintings and many gorgeous sculptures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling exhausted from our day, we grabbed a beer and some fries and waited for the bus home.
This week will be my last at the internship: I will begin my two weeks of travel with my friends from home soon.
It will be very nice to see my friends again and it is going to be a good change of pace to stop working.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/Brussels/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Brussels/</guid>
        
        
        <category>germany</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weekend July 20th: Fairs, Fun, and Staying Home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Describing a relaxing, non travelling weekend in Dortmund and Dusseldorf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;back-in-dortmund&quot;&gt;Back in Dortmund&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend I decided to take a much needed break from travelling and stay at home with some friends.
I didn’t exactly stay at &lt;em&gt;home&lt;/em&gt; though because all of my friends from the program are still in Dortmund.
If I haven’t told you, I was required to move to Dusseldorf for my internship with SMS.
The train ride from Dusseldorf to Dortmund is about an hour and a half if you are lucky.
For almost the first time in a month and a half, I was lucky! The train ride went without any interruptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that I noticed back in Dortmund is that the town had quickly become small.
After travelling all over Germany and seeing many different areas, Dortmund didn’t seem unusually different.
The quaint German houses, the brick lined streets, and the bustling train station were nothing new to me at this point and it was comforting to know that in my travels I have adapted to an entirely different way of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It being a weekend, I couldn’t take the hanging rail to my dorm. Now that I finally have a camera, I got some good shots of what the forest looks like in between my old dorm and the rest of campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DormWalk.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Walk from Dorm to Campus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;going-out-in-the-city&quot;&gt;Going out in the City&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was nice to finally see Andy and Wanda again and I was also introduced to Andy’s friend Hannah who was visiting from Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DortmundClubbing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hanging out with friends again!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being around the Ruhr fellows was a welcome break from seeing mostly Germans every day.
We found some clubs that were fun and some that were funny that night. 
My personal highlight of the night was going to a club that was basically unattended.
We were essentially the only four people on the dance floor when they started blaring a very eery remix of “Fresh Prince of Bel Air”, which probably stands as the weirdest thing I have heard in a club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;daytime-dortmund&quot;&gt;Daytime Dortmund&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day Andy and Hannah decided to go hiking, so Wanda and I ran some errands in Dortmund.
I finally made it to the Post Office so I could send some gifts home to my family.
On the outside of the Post Office were these two amazing statues of Hand People!
They clearly symbolize the Ruhr Area’s deindustrialization and the people’s fading identification with manual labor, as well as the painful struggle for new work.
Plus, the Hand-People have butts, which is hilarious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/HandStatues.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hand Statues&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that we finally made it to the resturaunt that our German teacher Matthaus told us about, the KartoffelLord! 
It is a small hipster restuaraunt that only sells potatoes and other vegetarian dishes (for Germany vegetarian is a big deal).
The portions were huge and delicious. I would love to go back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/KartoffelLord.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kartoffel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;dusseldorf-fair&quot;&gt;Dusseldorf Fair&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near dinnertime Wanda and I left for Dusseldorf to go see the amusement park. 
This park is held every year, but only for a week or two.
All of the rides are built on the uninhabited side of the Rhein river just for this event, and my coworkers told me that people visit from the Netherlands and France just for the park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/BridgeView.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;View from Bridge&quot; /&gt;
The fair was absolutely packed with people, the train that we caught to the fair practically had people hanging out of the windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was plenty of good food at the fair! 
It was mostly traditional German food like giant pieces of meat or unreasonably large sausages or humongous pretzels filled with butter.
I wasn’t surprised to find that Germans could pull off fair food really well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/OlympicRings.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Olympic Rings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wanda and I went up on the Ferris wheel and on a massive roller coaster called the Olympic Rings. 
There were plenty of rides which ranged from little kid bumper cars to spinning, strobing, metal death traps. 
The food was cheap but the rides themselves were very expensive, which was the opposite of US parks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/FerrisWheel.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;View from Ferris Wheel&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/NightFair.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;View From Bridge (Again)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was a great day. Sunday was spent relaxing and getting the rest of my things in order. It’s always good to sit back and rest before the next adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/Dusseldorf_Fair/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Dusseldorf_Fair/</guid>
        
        
        <category>germany</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week One:Hallo! Ich bin David.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An explanation of the first week of my trip through Germany! This post covers airports, Cologne, and some great food and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;arriving-across-the-pond&quot;&gt;Arriving Across the Pond&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived in Düsseldorf Internation Airport on June 1st after going through the longest flight in my life.
On the flight I watched Birdman and Interstellar for free.
Both of the movies were really interesting, but when I arrived in Düsseldorf I regretted not having the extra sleep. 
The other person arriving at the time was Nick Gailey, a Ruhr Fellow from Berkeley.
He was very nice and down to earth.
This is either his second or third time in Germany so I think I will be coming to him for German help throughout the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We met our German doubles at the train station and made it back to the dorms in TU Dortmund in one piece. I met most of the other Ruhr Fellows in front of the train station at the University and we set off to the main city.
At the first stop a Ruhr Fellow named Charles thought it was the city so we all ended up leaving the train. 
Because we got off at the wrong station we had to wait for almost an hour for the next train.
I didn’t mind too much because it gave us plenty of time to get to know the other Ruhr Fellows.
Luckily most of them also do not really speak German, so I don’t feel too embarrassed that my language is on the level of a small toddler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we finally arrived at the city Laura (the program director) treated us all to dinner. 
The burger and beer that I ordered were delicious and a great introduction to German food!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ich-spreche-kein-deutsch-introduction-to-german-lessons&quot;&gt;Ich spreche kein deutsch: Introduction to German lessons&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a few classes that we are required to take for the first month: daily German language class, weekly Culture/Technology courses with other TU students, and a weekly private series on culture.
Most of our time is going to be spent visiting the Ruhr area and the companies located there.
We seem to be mostly meeting with CEOs, politicians, and academics.
I guess you could say we are high-profile Americans living in Germany for this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The German lessons seem to be going pretty slow. Every time I learn a phrase I am reminded of how many I simply do not know. 
Whenever I want to ask to use the bathroom, ask for the price of something, or introduce myself I can only think of how to say things in Spanish.
The good news is that I learned a lot of Spanish throughout High School.
The even better news is that this is just making me more determined to learn German.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-doubles&quot;&gt;The Doubles&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were also introduced to our German doubles this week. These doubles are also students in our Culture and Technology class. 
My double’s name is Dennis. 
He speaks perfect English and is very friendly.
My main goal this month is to have a casual conversation with him in German.
After meeting the doubles Dennis introduced me to FlunkeBall, a drinking game known throughout Germany. 
The goal is to knock over a bottle of water that has been placed between the two teams. 
The team that knocks the bottle over gets to drink until the other team puts the bottle back upright. 
The first team to finish all of their beers wins.
My introduction to this game illustrates the differences in drinking culture between Germany and the United States. 
In Germany the game is set up so that it is the winners that are drinking. 
This prevents the negative feedback loop seen in America where the losers continually get worse at the game.
It also solidifies drinking beer as something that is positive and part of the culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-first-free-day-a-trip-to-kln-cologne&quot;&gt;The First Free Day: A trip to Köln (Cologne)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had the first Thursday free for a religious holiday so we decided to travel to Cologne.
The Cologne Cathedral was the first thing that we saw outside of the train station. 
It is an awe-inspiring building and it is one of the largest pieces of intricate architecture I have ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cologne.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Cathedral&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience was enhanced by the fact that the holiday was being celebrated at the Cathedral. 
We soon found ourselves stuck in a crowd lining a pack of priests and large procession of people in red and white outfits.
While we couldn’t understand what was going on, it was a pretty interesting and a good start to the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/procession.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Processon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch Andy, Wanda and I visited the Ludwig Museum of Modern Art. 
The museum had the largest standing collection of Picassos. 
I found all of the exhibits to be very interesting, they had some very beautiful abstract paintings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/abstract.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Abstract Painting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished the trip by walking across the Hohenzollern bridge.
This is one of Europe’s lock bridges.
This means that couples put a lock on the bridge and throw the key into the Rhine river to symbolize their lasting relationship.
There were an unbelievable amount of locks on the bridge of all different shapes and sizes.
We even heard from someone that many of the locks were taken down because their combined weight were threatening the bridge.
If I read that fact in a novel I would think that the author was being a little heavy handed with the symbolism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/lockbridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lock Bridge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;an-event-with-the-chancellor-a-trip-to-bochum&quot;&gt;An Event with the Chancellor: A trip to Bochum&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Saturday of the first week we had a large even in Bochum University, the sister university to TU Dortmund. 
The event was being held to celebrate Bochum’s 50th anniversary. 
Bochum is one of the first &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; universities that was created in the Ruhr area and it is apparently very dear to the German people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/bochum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bochum&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event consisted of dancers, an orchestra, and a speech by the German President, Joachim Gauck. 
The event would have been great except for the fact that we were never really given food and it was dragging on until the afternoon. 
What started out as one of the fanciest events quickly became a sort of foodless prison.
We were all happy when we were able to come back to Dortmund so we could start our real weekend, catch up on some much needed sleep, and finally go food shopping.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/Week_One/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Week_One/</guid>
        
        
        <category>germany</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is is my first post! For the upcoming summer this blog is going to be mostly about my two month trip to Germany.
I will be leaving on May 31st and arriving in Dortmund on June 1st. For the first month I’ll be studying at Dortmund University, mostly learning German.
The second month I will be working at &lt;a href=&quot;www.sms-siemag.com&quot;&gt;SMS Siemag Aktiengesellschaft&lt;/a&gt;. 
If anyone is going to be around the area or wants to practice German please let me know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The posts that aren’t personal will deal with cool things that I find or do in computer science. 
This blog is currently written with [Jekyll] (http://jekyllrb.com/) and hosted for free on [github pages] (https://pages.github.com/). 
I chose Jekyll for the blog because the entire website is kept in plain-text markdown.
This lets me writeup everything with whatever editor I want (vim!) and it allows me to write and make changes without internet.
I can store the whole blog on my chromebook and push to github whenever I happen to have internet access. 
Jekyll also allows me to host the site locally and the templating system is very similar to Django!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/Hello_World/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Hello_World/</guid>
        
        
        <category>personal,coding</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
